Serge Durand

Software Engineer and Full Stack Developer

contact@serge.codes

https://serge.codes https://linkedin.com/in/sergedurand205

EXPERIENCE

Python developer

URL Shortener - tinyy.ink | youtu.be/xX9J4LlkRl8 10/2022 - 11/2022

- Developed a web application to convert long links into shorter ones. Supports QR code generation and charts for statistics.
- Redis-based cache server is used for high-performant and near real-time reads.
- Uses CAPTCHA to enhance security by preventing bots and DOS attacks.

Senior Javascript developer

Thesis Follow up - edc-stg.online | tinyy.ink/stg-demo 06/2022 - 08/2022

- I led a team of 5 developers in the development of a platform for following up the thesis of postgraduate students in my university; tech stack consists of Mongodb, Expressjs, React & Nodejs (MERN)
- Implemented a robust API for front and backend communication and raised throughput of CORS requests by over 30%.
- Thanks to my leadership and Agile management skills, the project was completed a week prior to its pre-assigned completion date. I used Jira to track issues and tasks.

Software developer - Internship

TechniqConsulting

12/2021 - 03/2022

- Internship at an IT consultancy and software development company.
- Thanks to my broad expertise, clients requirements were more easily understood and properly implemented. This led to a noticeable increase in customer satisfaction and hence customer base.

Python developer

CS Portal - camerschools.site | youtu.be/6LdmxpaATBs 06/2021 - 10/2021

- Developed a platform that offers many services to users such as buying, selling and requesting items, publishing lost and found items, asking questions and discussing various topics.
- It is deployed on the cloud(Azure) with a microservices architecture backed by Docker and DBMS based on Postgres, all sitting on a Django implementation.

React/Nextjs developer

Amicopy Frontend - amicopy.vercel.app 05/2021 - 05/2021

• Template website with home, pricing and auth pages.

SUMMARY

Pragmatic and experienced software engineer who is well-versed in technology and writing code to create reliable and user-friendly systems. I'm also a skilled leader who has proven the ability to educate and manage a team of professionals to build software, while improving and learning from fellow collaborators.

SKILLS

Software Architecture

Docker

CI/CD & DevOps

Scrum & Agile Development

Prototype Development

Project Management

LANGUAGES

English Native
French Native

EDUCATION

Computer Science

University of Yaoundé 1 2022

Bachelor's degree

• I led a team of 5 developers that developed a platform for my university to follow up the thesis of postgraduate students.

CERTIFICATES

DevOps Essentials (IBM)

11/2022 - Present

Enslish Speaking - Expert (Emmersion)

12/2022 - 04/2023